我们被称为密特拉之子
We are known as the Sons of Mithras.
鬼火 这就是密特拉神之子的杰作
Ignis fatuus, that's what this Sons of Mithras business is.
如果我娶了卡米拉・帕吉...
If I marry Camilla Pazzi...
你我仍然可以不时地偷欢
You and I can still snatch a little freedom here and there.
要在洛伦佐过来的路上动手吗?
Do we kill Lorenzo coming up the path?
只有他们兄弟两个在一起的时候 我们才能动手
Strike only when the brothers are together.
卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂?
Lucrezia Donati?
备马去锡耶纳 我们当面问她
Saddle the horses for Siena. We'll question her directly.
- 这位就是最后一位救世主  - 先生们
- And here's our final savior.  - Gentlemen.
是什么让你背叛洛伦佐 背叛我们大家?
What possesses you to betray Lorenzo, to betray us all?
- 你是卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂的父亲  - 是的
- You are Lucrezia Donati's father.  - Indeed.
艺术家 我看到你逃出来了
L'Artista, I see you escaped.
而我看到了一把钥匙
And I see a key.
科西莫・美第奇是密特拉之子
Cosimo de Medici was a Son of Mithras.
一艘装了探险补给的船
A ship provisioned for a journey.
天穹就在那
The Vault of Heaven is out there.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Spencer
翻译：落寞卷菜 潇妹纸 凌凡1991 Harry妹子 SceneryJuly Mabb
校对：sharefans_竺 影子
达芬奇的恶魔 第一季第8集
君士坦丁堡 13年前
真主至上
Allahu Akbar.
阿尔拉希姆 密特拉之子的命运如何?
What does the future hold for the Sons of Mithras, Al-Rahim?
占卜是难以捉摸的
Augury is a tricky business.
我看到了愤怒的潮水
I see grim tidings.
无尽的黑暗和绝望
Darkness, despair.
一如既往的疯言疯语啊
The usual cant and caper, then.
你会让情况好起来的 对吗 科西莫・美第奇?
You would make light of our circumstances, Cosimo de Medici?
当然了 我的朋友 唯一支撑我的就是光明
Light is the only thing that sustains me, my friend.
地平线上有福音出现吗?
Are there no bright spots on the horizon, then?
有一个从芬奇来的男孩
There is one, a boy from Vinci.
他大有希望
He has promise.
即便使诈 也要把他带到佛罗伦萨
Even now, events conspire to bring him to Florence.
需要我盯他吗?
Am I to keep an eye on him?
别靠太近
Only from a distance.
他必须靠自己的创造成功或者失败
He must ascend or fall by his own devices.
说到创造
And speaking of devices,
我们请你保护它的安全
we give you this for safe-keeping.
时候到了 自然有人会来找它
Someone will come for this when it is time to make the journey.
或许就是那个阿尔拉希姆提到的男孩
Perhaps, the boy Al-Rahim speaks of.
如果他能捱过磨难的话
Assuming he survives his trial.
我相信 他会的
I have faith he will.
如果要我保护火种的话
If I'm to keep the candles burning,
要许我以保证 而不能仅仅有飘渺的信念和模糊的预言
I'll need more reassurances than faith and a vague prophecy.
恐怕我不能给你任何保证
I'm afraid I cannot give you any reassurances.
如果卜卦显示的命运成真
If the future indicated by these signs comes to pass,
我们中就只有一个人能活到那时候
only one of us will live to see it.
那么是谁能够幸存?
So which lucky one gets to survive?
你错了
You misunderstand.
死去的才是幸运的人
The dead will be the lucky ones.
活下来看到未来的人...
The one who lives to see this future...
会备受折磨
he will truly suffer.
我会想念这个地方的
I'm going to miss this place.
还有你们 我会十分挂念的 我的朋友们
And you. I'll miss you as well, my friends.
我们愿意继续跟随你
We've followed you into more scrapes than I care to count.
为什么不带着我们?
Why not add another to the tally?
我不能请求你们跟随我漂洋过海
I can't ask you to follow me across an ocean.
我们愿意 大师
We want to, Maestro.
天穹 叶之书 当你找到他们的时候
The Vault of Heaven, the Book of Leaves,
我们想陪在你身边
we want to be there when you find them.
这孩子够蠢的
The boy's a half-wit moon-calf
就算你让他把小弟弟插在牛粪里 他也会照办的
who'd smother his balls in ox dung if you told him to.
至于我? 我赌债累累
As for me? I've accrued some gambling debts
都付不起在佛罗伦萨的快到期的房租了
that make my near-term residence in Florence problematic.
下一站是哪儿呢? 我们需要一艘船 对吧?
So where to next? We'll need a ship, won't we?
葡萄牙人和西非的贸易往来
The Portuguese are establishing
日益频繁
trade routes along Western Africa.
我们要乘船去卡纳里岛
We'll book passage to the Canary Islands.
之后 就走一步算一步
After that, we'll have to improvise.
不过首先 我要去和美第奇家族算一笔帐
First, I've certain accounts to settle with the House of Medici.
为什么扯上美第奇家族? 为什么还不彻底抛下佛罗伦萨的事情?
Why bother with the Medicis? Why not skirt Florence entirely?
有些事 我必须要和洛伦佐说
There are things I have to say to Lorenzo.
只能亲口跟他说
Words for his ears alone.
那我们今晚在吠犬酒店碰头?
Shall we meet at the Barking Dog this evening?
为什么不呢? 喝一品脱酒 最后一次突袭佛罗伦萨人 碰碰运气
Why not? A pint, one last foray into a Florentine slit for luck.
我们还能看看尼科胆量如何
We can see if Nico's balls have dropped.
奇怪
That's odd.
地中海隼
That's a Lanner Falcon.
他们很少出现在亚德里亚海边
They're rare this side of the Adriatic.
在土耳其和非洲还有可能见到 但是这儿?
Turkey, Africa, yes. But here?
- 说不定它迷路了 有可能  - 不
- It lost its way. It happens.  - No, not often.
最后一次我看见这种鸟是
The last time I saw a Lanner
在我母亲离开那天
was the day my mother disappeared.
- 你说它们来自土耳其?  - 嗯
- You say they hail from Turkey?  - Mm.
我打赌这只鸟对你来说是个恶兆
I'll wager that bird's an omen, meant for you alone.
我该跟着它
I should follow it.
我说了 这是恶兆 如果真有什么事情 你也该往反方向跑啊
I said it's an omen. If anything, you should ride in the opposite direction.
- 我们酒店见  - 莱昂!
- I'll meet you at the Dog.  - Leo!
驾!
Yah!
我敢说 现在你相信梦...
I take it you now believe in visions...
和恶魔了?
and demons?
朱利亚诺去哪儿了?
Where can be Giuliano be?
联姻的事 你和他谈得有多糟糕?
How badly did you handle your talk with him about this marriage?
他知道他必须娶这个女孩
He knew he had to wed the girl.
他也认为没有别的办法
He agreed there was no other way
来平息和帕吉家的世仇了
to halt our feud with the Pazzis,
但我好多天都没看见他了
yet I've not seen a trace of him for days.
你是听到他说"愿意"两个字
Did you actually hear him utter the words, "I agree",
还是只听了你想听到的部分?
or did you only hear what you wanted to hear?
他就是同意了
He agreed.
朱利亚诺可能根本不会来了
Giuliano may not arrive at all.
我们行动吧
I say we strike.
趁洛伦佐和克拉丽丝都在 杀了他们
Kill Lorenzo and Clarice while we have them here.
你想用你的愚蠢来成全对手的成功吗?
Are you so blind to the success of your rivals?
民意向着他们兄弟二人
The brothers are popular.
杀一个 只会让幸存者
Murdering only one will allow the survivor
更有能力团结民众来对付我们
to rally the city against us.
只有在同时失去兄弟两个的重创下
Only with the shock of losing both men at once
佛罗伦萨才会接受新的领导者
will Florence bow to new leaders.
不管朱利亚诺在哪里 你都可以派人杀了他
You can send your men after Giuliano, wherever he is.
我能自己解决洛伦佐
I can handle Lorenzo myself.
如果这么做 弗朗切斯科 你就忤逆了罗马的意志
Do so and you defy the will of Rome, Francesco.
我现在警告你
I warn you now.
太神奇了
Remarkable.
据说
According to lore,
这把钥匙能打开天穹
these will open the Vault of Heaven.
那个阿比西尼亚人 所罗门・奥拜告诉你具体方位了吗?
Solomon Ogbai, the Abyssinian, told you its location?
他跟我说
He told me it rested
在古老山脉上的一座石头小镇里
on an old peak, in a town made of stone.
天穹就在太阳之柱下面
Beneath something called "the hitching post of the sun."
有了这把钥匙和去天穹的地图
With these keys and the map to the Vault itself,
叶之书就牢牢掌握在我们手中了
it would appear the Book of Leaves lies firmly within our grasp.
叶之书最后一次出现是什么时候?
When was the last time the Book was actually seen?
千年之前
A thousand years ago.
亚历山大图书馆被烧毁之际
When the Library of Alexandria burned.
但我们相信它存在着
Yet we still have faith it exists.
相信
Faith.
总是这样 不是吗?
It always comes down to that, doesn't it?
从没有什么事情得到证明 只是...
Never anything that can be proven. Just...
只是弥漫的烟雾
It's just smoke.
只是篝火旁的童话
It's tales by the camp fire.
你生气了
You're angry.
西斯笃教皇说你是土耳其的人
Pope Sixtus claims you're an agent of the Ottomans.
密特拉之子是不会
The Sons of Mithras are not constrained
受地理界限所限的
by geographic borders.
我们的使命关乎整个人类
Our stewardship encompasses all mankind.
那么 我这个独立的个体
Well, this particular man
厌倦了被操纵
is tired of being manipulated.
如果你在森林里迷路的时候看见了一个路标
If you are lost in a forest and you see a landmark,
那么你能说这个路标在操纵着你通往出口吗?
is that landmark manipulating you along a certain path?
我只是你的引导者
I am merely your guide.
但如果我不走你选的路...
But if I ignore your chosen path, then...
我就永远找不到母亲了 对吧?
I'll never find my mother, will I?
她可真可怜
She's a poor little thing.
如果我弟弟坏了这场宴会 那卡米拉・帕吉伤不伤心
Mending Camilla Pazzi's heart will be the least of our concerns
就无关紧要了
if my brother sabotages this feast.
我们的怠慢或许会使血战愈演愈烈
The snub could propel us all into still more years of blood feud.
看看弗朗切斯科 看看他们
Look at Francesco. Look at them all.
- 帕吉家在强压怒火  - 没错
- The Pazzis glower like that. - Exactly.
今天本该是来解决矛盾的
Today was supposed to be different.
我们还要等多久?
How long should we wait?
别总是那么没耐性 弗朗切斯科
Always so impatient, Francesco.
去和他们说说话
Talk with them.
抱怨朱利亚诺的缺席
Complain of the scandal of Giuliano's absence.
你对那个狗杂种的愤怒
Your anger at the cur's impudence
能很好的掩饰你的杀机
will disguise your desire to kill.
或者只能刺激我提前动手
Or it may just spur me to strike even faster.
队长 你的特长是知道佛罗伦萨人的行踪
Captain, tracking the comings and goings of Florentines is your specialty.
我的弟弟在哪儿?
Where is my brother?
我不知道
I cannot say.
一周之前 我的手下博蒂诺请命
A week ago, my Officer Bertino asked permission
陪同朱利亚诺去锡耶纳
to accompany Giuliano to Siena.
从那儿以后 我再没见过他们
I've seen neither of them since.
为什么去锡耶纳?
Why Siena?
朱利亚诺
Giuliano,
显然是想在结婚之前再疯狂一把
apparently longed for one last fling before his nuptials.
博蒂诺很忠诚 他发誓会保护他的
The pious Bertino promised to keep him from too much trouble.
但如果博蒂诺出事了呢?
What if Bertino failed?
如果朱利亚诺遭到埋伏了呢?
What if Giuliano was waylaid on the road?
当然 这会是他用缺席来羞辱我们的
Surely that's the only reason he'd insult us
唯一解释
with his absence today.
带上你的人 在佛罗伦萨和锡耶纳之间
Take a few men and search the roads
沿路搜寻
between Florence and Siena.
队长 我们都非常迫切想知道朱利亚诺的下落
All of us yearn to know what has become of Giuliano, Captain.
尽快为我们找到他 谢谢
Settle the matter for us. Please.
有一艘停在佛得角的船 皇冠蜥蜴号
There is a ship bound for Cape Verde, the Basilisk.
那是安东尼奥・诺里的船
Under the command of Antonio de Noli.
我们讲话的时候 诺里正在佛罗伦萨
As we speak, de Noli is in Florence,
往船上运送配给 为他的旅途做准备
loading a barge with provisions for a journey.
黎明时 他会启程去往比萨
At dawn, he takes the barge to Pisa,
就是皇冠蜥蜴号下锚的地方
where the Basilisk is anchored.
莱昂纳多 你必须乘那艘船去
You, Leonardo, must book passage on that ship.
凭你的航海技术
With your navigational skills,
皇冠蜥蜴号才能扛过暴风雨
the Basilisk will survive the storms
抵达另一片陆地
and reach another land entirely,
也就是叶之书所在的地方
where the Book of Leaves awaits.
多年以前 一个魔术士答应我为你藏一件东西
Some years ago, a magician promised me he would hide something for you.
魔术士?
A magician?
科西莫・美第奇?
Cosimo de Medici?
科西莫墓里有一个航海星盘
Cached within Cosimo's tomb is a mariner's astrolabe.
利用它你能判别方向 驾驶皇冠蜥蜴号
With it, you will navigate the Basilisk safely
到达地图上标记的地方
to the lands indicated on the map.
科西莫把它藏了起来 只有你能解开谜 找到它
Cosimo hid it in a way that only you would solve his riddle.
又要像以前一样 用你的游戏来玩弄我吗
As ever, you know the right games to tantalize me.
你必须带着星盘上驳船
You must carry the astrolabe onto that barge.
关乎你母亲命运的叶之书
The Book of Leaves, of your mother's fate,
仍是一个谜
will remain a mystery.
这不该是你旋转硬币
Isn't this the moment where you spin a coin,
来迷惑我的时候了吗?
put me into a trance?
没有硬币
No coins.
没有迷惑
No trances.
要么选西部走廊 要么不选
You either book passage West or you don't.
要么成功 要么失败
You succeed or you fail.
决定由你来做 后果由你来承担
The choice and the consequences are yours.
- 别紧张 孩子  - 我快病了
- Be still, child.  - I'm going to be sick.
你已经病了 没病谁也不会找我
You're already sick. No-one calls for me if they're well.
给 夹紧
Here. Hold this.
你没从坟上跨过吧?
You've not stepped over a grave, have you?
没喝本来要倒掉的牛奶吧?
Or drunk milk that's gone to spoil?
没 奥塔维亚 没干过那样的事
No, Ottavia. Nothing like that.
给 尿进去
Here. Piss into this.
上周我见到一个屠夫的女儿 因类似的病症而哭闹
I saw a butcher's daughter last week, blubbering on about a malady akin to this.
不得不把她剖开 里边全是虫子
Had to split her open. Worms.
天啊 这么浑浊
Oh. Cloudy as a winter's dawn.
很严重吗?
Is that bad?
每两天吃一小撮这个
A pinch or two of this every two days,
还有 别见月光了
and be sure to stay out of the light of the moon.
- 不是为了你 是为了他  - 为谁?
- Not for your sack, but for his.  - For whom?
你儿子 你也知道虫子跑哪去了 你怀孕了
Your son, you know where the worms go, you're with child.
带我去见他
Bring me to him.
不管你带来了什么噩耗 克拉丽丝都不会看到
I've sent Clarice away to spare her whatever tragedy you may have brought here.
别再拖延了 给我看看
Delay no more. Show me.
我的属下博蒂诺 被发现死在去锡耶纳的路上
My Officer Bertino. Found on the road to Siena.
被砍死的 是强盗干的吗?
Hacked to death. Bandits?
很有可能 不过没找到朱利亚诺的踪迹
Most likely. Yet we found no trace of Giuliano.
多带些人去 找到他 活要见人 死要见尸
Take more men. Find him, alive or dead.
我一定要知道弟弟的命运
I must know my brother's fate.
我这是在哪儿?
Where am I?
先生 你在埃尔萨谷口
In the Val d'Elsa, Signor.
我们从河里救出你时 你一只半脚都踏进鬼门关了
We found you in the river, more dead than alive.
我给你包扎了伤口
I nursed your wounds.
谢谢你
I thank you for that.
一看衣服就知道 你是个贵人
Soon as I seen your clothes, I knew you was a nobleman.
可你却没抢劫我
And yet, you didn't rob me.
抢劫不是基督徒的作风
Wouldn't be Christian.
今天周几? 我昏迷了多久?
What day is it? How long have I been out?
先生 今天是圣周六
Holy Saturday, Signor.
是基督尸体入坟的日子
When they laid Christ's body in the tomb.
啊呀!
Argh!
我得回佛罗伦萨去
I have to get back to Florence.
我要去提醒洛伦佐
I need to warn Lorenzo.
你需要休息 小伙子
You need to rest, son.
我不能休息
I can't.
没时间了
No time.
呵 死人还能走路
Hm. The dead still walk.
我以为你早死了
I assumed you had to be dead.
有人说你去了瓦拉吉亚 还有人说你去了罗马
Some said you traveled to Wallachia, others to Rome.
- 你去了哪里?  - 都去了
- Which was it?  - Both.
啊 都去了
Ah. Both.
那为何要在此相见?
So why are we meeting here? Hm?
你这次又想让我卷进什么阴谋?
What intrigue are you involving me in this time?
这是你为科西莫设计的坟墓吧?
This tomb, you designed it for Cosimo?
可以这么说
To an extent.
这座坟墓会不会
Like Cosimo's portrait,
像科西莫的画一样 隐含着什么秘密呢?
is it possible this tomb contains secret mysteries?
瞧瞧这些马赛克 这些圈圈
This mosaic, see how the circles
在整个设计中的编制样式
weave through the design.
后退 只看这东西
Step back and focus only on that.
所罗门王的结
King Solomon's Knot.
代表着永恒智慧的古老符号
The ancient symbol representing the wisdom of eternity.
没错
Yes.
众生均为凡事所扰
Other men live among the trappis of this world.
独独科西莫的思想
But Cosimo's face was always turned beyond
不被世俗所动
worldly distractions
而只关注世俗之上的宇宙
to the universe above.
他思维敏捷 世所罕见...
He had the most agile mind I've ever known...
你与他不相上下
until I met you.
过奖了
You honor me.
对我来说 你是最接近父亲这个称谓的人了
You're the closest thing I've ever known to a father.
我即将再次离开你
I'm about to leave you again.
这一次是可能回不来的追寻之旅
This time, on a quest from which I may never return.
你所回答的每一个问题 都会牵出另外的问题
Every question you answer leads to another question.
这样的追寻 得到的只有痛苦
And such quests lead many to nothing but misery.
真正的痛苦
The true misery
是所有的问题都被解决了
is if all the questions are solved,
那时候就再也没什么可问的了
cos then there's nothing left to ask.
- 你如今想到哪里去?  - 这要看我在这儿的发现
- Where do you voyage now?  - It depends on what I find here.
我不会不辞而别
I designed no secret compartment.
啊! 但是...
Ah! But...
但是魔术师
but the Magician
可以神不知鬼不觉地实施
could install one without anyone knowing.
就像瑕疵一样
Like a flaw.
科西莫不会这么做的
Cosimo would never have permitted it.
而且...
And yet...
瞧 快看! 看到没?
Look. Look! Do you see?
这和所罗门王的结里的半圆
It's exactly the same as the semi-circles
完全一模一样
in King Solomon's Knot.
而科斯莫的关注点
And Cosimo's gaze reflected
也反映在天秤座上
on Libra,
即平衡的天秤上
the scales of balance.
或许有相应的偏差?
Perhaps there's a matching discrepancy?
这儿 看到没? 那儿 看吧
Here. Do you see? There. Look.
它们是不是构成了一条轴线?
Do they form an axis?
这样的话 必定会有另外一条轴线与之相交
Well, if so, then there must be another axis that crosses it.
没错
Exactly.
从这里开始
Starting here.
那它的交点应该在...
Then its mate would be...
这儿 快看
Here. Look.
结的中心
The center of the knot
应该会...
would be...
在心脏的正上方
directly above the heart.
这个问题解决了
The question answered.
也就又有了问题
Which leads to another question.
没错
Yes.
确实如此
Magnificently so.
先生!
Signor!
美第奇阁下 你去了哪里?
Signor Medici, where have you been?
你出什么事了?
What's befallen you?
背叛 队长 能借一步说话吗?
Treachery. A moment alone, Captain?
博蒂诺和我确认了卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂是间谍
Bertino and I determined Lucrezia Donati to be a spy.
你不是认真的吧
You cannot mean it.
我们在锡耶纳找到了她 正好碰见一队强盗袭击她
We sought her out in Siena, and came across her being attacked by bandits.
我们击退了强盗 但是博蒂诺却牺牲了
We dispatched them but at the cost of Bertino's life.
卢克蕾齐娅捅了我
Lucrezia stabbed me.
以为我死了
Left me for dead.
她是瑞阿里奥和西斯笃教皇的间谍
She is an agent of Riario and Pope Sixtus.
卡波尔蒂! 骑马跟布莱克・马丁先走 告诉洛伦佐 朱利亚诺还活着
Capaldi! Ride with Black Martin. Tell Lorenzo Giuliano lives.
我会根据他的伤势跟上你们的 走 快走!
I will escort him home at a pace his wounds allow. Go. Go!
谢谢你 队长 考虑得真周到
Thank you, Captain, for your consideration.
这不算什么
It is nothing.
总得有人来关照你
Someone needs to tend to you.
我们有过合约
We had a contract.
你违反它 我就有权
You break it and I will be justified
剥夺你的自由
in depriving you of your freedom.
那上次那个把我
And what happened to the last man
关进佛罗伦萨监狱的人怎么样了?
who tried to pen me up in Florence?
你会发现比起那个倒霉的法官
You'll find me more of a match to you
我更配做你的对手
than that hapless magistrate.
的确
I would.
赠你一片封地如何?
What about a small duchy of your own?
这样你就可以自由地学习
That would give you the freedom to amass
你想学习的知识了
all the knowledge you like.
你手边的领地多到
And you have duchies sitting around
可以随便分发了吗?
to hand out like party favors?
乌尔比诺公爵和我已经同盟对抗教皇
The Duke of Urbino and I made an alliance to move on the Papacy.
我们很快就会有能力
That will give us the ability to give you
给你从来没有过的赏赐
the legitimacy you have never had.
我恐怕你的同盟已经胎死腹中
I suspect your alliance is dead.
我在梵蒂冈亲眼看到了乌尔比诺公爵
At the Vatican I saw the Duke of Urbino himself.
他可不是容易忽视的人 他在那相当自在
One can't miss the man. He looked quite at home.
你离我而去以后 还来告诉我 我唯一
So as you desert me, you bring me word that
能依赖的军事防御力量
my only other source of military defense
已经不能指望了?
is a sham?
你找上他也是以为他能够被收买 不是吗?
You approached him because you knew he had a price, yes?
有人出价比你高
Someone outbid you.
胡说
Fuck you.
总有艺术家找上我
Artists approach me all the time.
满脑子模糊又堂皇的想法
They are full of vague and glorious ideas
可他们从来没实现过
on which they rarely deliver.
这就是个例子
Case in point.
有人警告过你
You were warned.
有人在这间屋子里就警告过你
You were warned in this very room.
我收了很多酬金却完成了很少的任务
I accept many commissions, I finish few.
我给了你成为最风光的艺术家的机会
I gave you the chance to be the foremost artist of your day.
我把佛罗伦萨最有魅力的女人给你做模特
I gave you the most desirable woman in Florence as a subject.
她从来都不是我的模特
She was never my subject.
你我都爱这座城市 不是吗?
You and I love this city, do we not?
没错
We do.
那就帮我拯救她
Then help me save it.
我还能给你什么?
What else can I give you?
她怎么样?
What about her?
她的丈夫显然不是个问题
Her husband's clearly not an obstacle.
你认为我会这么轻易地就把她让给你?
You think I would just toss her to you just like that?
你已经有个妻子了
You have a wife.
同样美丽 同样需要你的关心
Who has her charms. Who needs attention.
卢克蕾齐娅对你来说有多重要 洛伦佐?
How much does Lucrezia mean to you, Lorenzo?
你愿意为了把我留在佛罗伦萨
Are you willing to set aside your toy
而放弃你的玩偶吗?
to keep me in Florence?
大人 您的弟弟已经被找到了
Magnifico, your brother has been found.
朱利亚诺还活着
Giuliano is alive.
受伤了 但还活着
Wounded but alive.
谁弄伤了他?
Who wounded him?
卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂
Lucrezia Donati.
- 那她也活着?  - 似乎是的
- And she is also alive? - It appears so.
她为什么要攻击朱利亚诺?
What was she doing attacking Giuliano?
她知道你的计划了吗?
Did she know of your plans?
朱利亚诺手无寸铁 德拉戈纳迪在照顾他
Giuliano is unarmed and  in the care of Dragonetti.
他不会活着回到佛罗伦萨了
He won't live to see Florence again.
但如果有人知道朱利亚诺被杀了
But if people learn Giuliano has been killed,
洛伦佐会得到人民的支持
Lorenzo will rally the people behind him.
我们必须先拿下洛伦佐
We must strike at Lorenzo first.
复活节弥撒
Easter Mass.
明天黎明我们在洛伦佐的圣餐里动手脚
Dawn tomorrow we will poison Lorenzo in the very act
毒死他
of taking holy communion,
让奥尔西尼唯唯诺诺的虔诚见鬼去
and damn Cardinal Orsini's pious hesitations.
就像上帝亲自下手夺走独裁者的性命
It will look as if God himself has taken down the tyrant.
- 你叫什么名字?  - 卡波尔蒂
- What is your name?  - Capaldi.
去找巴尼奥内神父和马菲神父
Find Father Bagnone and Father Maffei.
让他们准备好给洛伦佐的圣饼
Have them prepare the Host for Lorenzo,
还有他妻子的
and his wife,
以及他所有女儿的
and all his daughters.
然后骑马去找德拉戈纳迪 确保朱利亚诺必死无疑
Then ride back to Dragonetti and make sure that Giuliano has met his death.
必不辱命 大人
Consider it done, my lord.
几小时之后... 佛罗伦萨就是我们的了
Within hours... we will own Florence.
但是为什么卢克蕾齐娅会让罗马利用?
But why would Lucrezia agree to act as Rome's catspaw?
西斯笃任人唯亲
Sixtus only rewards his own blood.
你知道他已经把他的六个侄子任命为红衣大主教了吗?
Did you know he's already rewarded six of his nephews as cardinals?
- 他很衷心  - 到了乱伦的地步
- He is loyal.  - To the point of incestuousness.
佛罗伦萨的美德在于
The virtue of a republic like Florence
能者才能居之
is that offices go to the most worthy,
能者才能上任
appointments are made only on merit.
我敢说你的职位是你通过努力取得的 德拉戈纳迪 对吧?
I dare say you earned your rank on the basis of achievement, Dragonetti?
的确
I did.
而你不止一次地证明了自己
And you demonstrate that repeatedly.
多亏了你违反宵禁的名单
The details in your curfew ledgers
没有它们 博蒂诺和我永远不会发现
without them, Bertino and I could never have uncovered
背叛洛伦佐的人
the name of Lorenzo's betrayer.
其实只需要花时间研究记录
All one needed was the time to study the records.
当然 你就有这个时间
And you had the time, of course.
我确实很认真地对待我的工作
I do take my work seriously.
所以她在宵禁后躲过了检查 对吧?
That's how she was able to avoid detection after curfew, isn't it?
她不在场理由很充分 忙着和我哥哥偷情
She had the perfect alibi, fucking my brother,
而第一个会怀疑她动向的人
and because the first man to raise questions about her activities
早就站到罗马那边了
was already in league with Rome himself.
我逃跑也没用
I could try and ride away.
你毫发未伤 马也更加健壮
But you're unwounded, your mount is fresher.
那就杀了我吧
Finish what your spy began, then.
或许她会跟你上床
Perhaps she'll reward you between her legs.
- 我想要的不是这个  - 那是什么?
- That is not what spurs me.  - What does?
渴望一个敬畏上帝的佛罗伦萨
A desire for a Florence that fears God,
而不是害怕主人的
not its masters.
我们去找你哥哥
Let's get to your brother's side.
诺里的船 开往比萨的吗?
De Noli's barge, bound for Pisa?
是的 先生
Aye, Signor.
订三个位置多少钱?
How much to book passage for three?
我们只运货物和行李
We take only freight and baggage.
告诉你了 只运货物和行李
I told you, only freight and baggage.
我必须登上王冠蜥蜴号
I have to board the Basilisk.
恩 这下看起来像行李了
Yeah, you're beginning to look like baggage.
明早黎明 别迟到
Dawn tomorrow. Don't be late.
每个队都在其中一个门附近
Each of my brigades awaits near one of these gates.
可以说佛罗伦萨已经在我们的掌控之下了
You may consider Florence already under our control.
- 你的人忠诚吗?  - 当然
- Your men are loyal to you?  - But of course.
如果他们军粮不足提前入侵的话
Because if they get battle-hungry and invade prematurely,
佛罗伦萨人会奋起反抗的
the Florentines will rise against them.
佛罗伦萨人只是店主和店员
The Florentines are shopkeepers and clerks.
我们是士兵
We're soldiers.
佛罗伦萨人住在狭窄的走廊和小巷中
The Florentines live in narrow corridors and alleyways
他们可以出其不意地攻击
where they can strike unexpectedly.
如果他们为保卫家园而奋起
If they rise to fight for their home,
将会有一场你从未见过的战斗
it will not resemble the fields of battle you know.
我们有新武器打街头战
We have new weapons for street warfare.
你要听我们指挥
You will follow our lead.
帕吉家族在此间的角色是推翻暴君
The Pazzis' role in all this is to overthrow the tyrants,
建立一个全新的王国
establish a clear new regime.
而你的角色只是被传唤的时候出现一下
While your role is only to appear if summoned
巩固即将成立的政权的地位
to cement the powers-that-will-be into place.
如果我选择单独进入佛罗伦萨...
If I choose to move on Florence myself...
你又凭什么阻拦我?
who are you to stop me?
告诉我 是谁养你的队伍的?
Tell me, who is it that pays your men?
你高高在上 给他们发军资
You sit in the middle, conveying their wages
用的可是罗马的钱
which issue from the vaults of Rome.
违背我
Act against me,
罗马会给你打上异教徒的烙印
and that same city shall brand you a heretic,
剥脱你的头衔 把你逐出教会
strip you of your titles, and excommunicate you.
继续反抗 大主教
Resist further, and His Holiness
会把你的金属眼罩熔化
will have that metal eyepiece of yours melted down
在纳沃纳广场浇到你的睾丸上
and poured over your testicles in the middle of the Piazza Navona.
我见识过他的能力... 是双眼所见
I've seen what he's capable of with... both of my eyes.
你的人回来了
Your man returns.
或许有我哥哥的消息
Perhaps with news from my brother.
他不是从大人那儿来的...
He comes not from Il Magnifico...
而是从瑞阿里奥伯爵那儿...
but from Count Riario...
确认我已经杀了你
to confirm I've killed you.
那他干嘛不带着我还活着的消息离开?
Why is he not riding away with news I'm still alive?
我想他另有打算
I think he has another plan.
停下
Hold.
- 你要做什么?  - 做对佛罗伦萨最好的事
- What are you doing?  - What's best for Florence.
啊!
Aargh!
捡起他的剑
Pick up his sword.
要救你哥哥 你需要武器
You'll need a weapon if you're going to save your brother.
快 朱利亚诺 趁我没改变主意
Do it now, Giuliano. Before I change my mind again.
是我
It's me.
你以为我听不出你的脚步声?
You think I don't know your footsteps?
给我个理由...
Give me a reason...
我为什么不现在就刺穿你的脖子
why I shouldn't puncture your neck this instant.
今天不行
Not today.
你给瓦妮莎下毒 我为救她差点变痴呆
You poisoned Vanessa and I risked dementia trying to save her.
你告诉了瑞阿里奥战争机器的秘密
You shared the secrets of my war machinery with Riario
让这座城市陷入危机
and put the city at peril.
这个... 这封揭发信
This... this denunciation
指控我性侵
that names me a sexual criminal,
把我投进监狱 等待火刑
had me thrown in jail to face the bonfire.
都是你干的好事!
This is your work!
是我让尼科把你带到修道院救你朋友的命
I had Nico send you to the convent to keep your friend alive.
审判时我为你求情
I begged for your mercy during the trial
树下了想取我性命的敌人
and made enemies who seek my life.
你不知道我冒了多大的险...
You will never understand the risks I have taken...
- 让你父亲活命  - 什么?
- To keep your father alive.  - What?
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
他希望我告诉你他有多爱你
He wishes me to tell you how much he loves you.
我在圣天使堡的监狱里和他谈过了
I spoke with him in his cell in Castel Sant'angelo.
然后你利用了他们对我的控制
Then you grasp the hold they have maintained over me.
这种控制太强大了...
It's a hold so strong...
让你对一个无辜的人下毒
that you would even poison an innocent man.
你为找你母亲又冒了多大的险呢?
And what of the risks you have faced in search of your mother?
哈?
Huh?
如果是你能决定她的生死
If it fell to you to keep her alive,
你会说"不 我宁可救另一个人的命"吗?
would you say "No, I'll preserve another's life"?
我会找到别的办法
I would find another way.
是啊 你说起来可真是轻松
Yeah, how easy it is for you to believe that.
我会理解你的行为 卢克蕾齐娅...
I would understand your actions, Lucrezia...
若不是你父亲拒绝了让他自由的机会
if your father hadn't rejected my offer to set him free.
- 你在撒谎  - 没有
- You're lying.  - No.
你犯的这些罪都是徒劳
You've committed these sins for nothing.
你的作品都想证明人是否无所不能
Your work argues that man is capable of anything.
你我就是证明
Well, between us, we prove it.
你展现了人类伟大的极限 而我是丑恶的极限
You show us the heights that we can reach and I show us the depths.
最近...
Of late...
我遇见了身居黑暗中的智者
I've met men who dwell in shadows,
他们对我提起... 另一个世界
speaking of... other times and other lives.
或许... 如果他们所说是真的...
Maybe... if they're correct...
有另一个世界存在于我们...
a life exists in which we...
是 是的
Yes. Yes.
是
Yes.
不行 我不能这样 我不能
No, I can't do this. I can't.
- 求求你 求求你  - 我不能 不能
- Please. Please.  - I can't. I can't.
我必须走了 我必须...
I have to go. I have to...
停在比萨的一条船将载我寻找叶之书
A ship waits in Pisa to take me to the Book of Leaves.
要是我没有登上王冠蜥蜴号...
If I'm not on the Basilisk...
瑞阿里奥和帕吉的军队已经逼近佛罗伦萨
Riario and the Pazzis are moving on Florence.
- 他们想杀洛伦佐  - 我不必在乎他们
- They want to kill Lorenzo.  - I could care less, what they do.
让政客们互相残杀吧 那是他们的专长
Let the politicians kill each other, that's their forte.
莱昂纳多 求求你 如今只有你能阻止这一切
Leonardo, please, you are only one who can stop this now.
要是你不愿为我和洛伦佐
If you're not going to do it for me or for Lorenzo,
请为佛罗伦萨阻止他们
then do it for Florence.
为佛罗伦萨?
For Florence?
为佛罗伦萨? 这座背叛我的城市?
For Florence? The city that turned its back on me?
我这个私生子?
The bastard son?
我这个鸡奸犯?
The sodomite?
从前的达芬奇可能会听你话 卢克蕾齐娅
A younger Da Vinci might've bought your arguments, Lucrezia.
但是... 几个月来我忍受的太多了
But... I've endured too much these last few months
我不再被情绪左右
to be swayed by sentiment.
现在是复活节
It's Easter.
如果佛罗伦萨需要祭品...
If Florence demands a sacrifice...
我建议你献上自己
I suggest you offer yourself.
你还在用那烟臭味污染空气呢
You still endeavor to taint the air with that foul stench, I see.
我的恶习
A vice.
但吉罗拉摩允许我抽烟
One that Girolamo sees fit to allow me.
你不只有一个恶习
Not the only one.
我不明白你为何对这游戏如此着迷
I've never understood your obsession with this game.
我想象你玩了几千遍
I imagine you've played thousands of times,
它能带你给什么?
and what has it brought you?
帮你知己
Know thy self,
帮你知彼
know thine enemy.
这不过是休闲游戏
It is but a recreation.
真正的谋略
True strategic mastery
只能在生活的竞技场上锻造
must be forged in the arena of life.
- 复活节快乐  - 的确快乐
- Happy Easter.  - Indeed.
因为今天不止基督复活...
For today brings not only the resurrection of Christ...
佛罗伦萨也将在罗马的统治下复兴
but the resurrection of Florence under Rome's rule.
很快 意大利诸国将会统一
Soon, all the Italian states will fall into line.
然后我将把转移注意力转移到
I will then turn my attention
上帝的真正敌人上...
to the true enemy of God...
奥斯曼帝国
the Ottoman Empire.
最后发动一场圣战
A final Holy War.
辉煌的胜利将使我被誉为...
A glorious victory for which I will be made...
一位圣者
a saint.
你一定要记得在人民面前
Beware of practicing your righteousness
表现自己的正直
before other people in order to be seen by them,
因为人民不会从你的上帝那里...
for then there will be no reward from your Father...
得到任何好处
who is in heaven.
我必须感谢你
I must thank you.
因为没有你 我不会有今天的成就
For without you, I could never have achieved today's triumph.
这样说 或许你应该给我...
And for this, perhaps you would offer me...
一点回报?
something in return?
嗯
Hmm.
现在是时候 你和我...
I believe it's time you and I...
再下一局了
played another game.
同意吧... 兄弟?
Don't you agree... Brother?
都准备好了?
Is all in place?
巴尼奥内和马菲神父正在准备毒药
Fathers Bagnone and Maffei are preparing the poison.
那大主教呢?
And the Cardinal?
他太他妈虔诚了 我没敢告诉他计划有变
He's too fucking pious to be told of this change of plans.
祈祷时 神父会把圣餐捧给洛伦佐
While he prays, the priests will deliver the tainted Eucharist to Lorenzo.
这人是夸特罗内 美蒂奇的忠诚支持者
Quattrone. Medici loyalist.
要是和我们作起对
If he goes against us,
他变成鬼也会支持洛伦佐
he'll join Lorenzo in the afterlife.
有达芬奇的消息吗?
Is there any news of Da Vinci?
上次我收到消息时 他还在罗马
The last I heard, he was in Rome.
他每次和咱们作对!
He's countered us again and again!
我们不知他的下落 还可以行动吗?
Can we act if we don't know the man's whereabouts?
镇定点 弗朗切斯科
Calm yourself, Francesco.
我们准备周全 一切待命
We have long prepared. All is ready.
女士 你让我这个老头...
Signorina, you make an old man...
也相信人看起来可以如此完美
believe in the perfectibility of mankind.
谢谢你 大师
Thank you, Maestro.
你怎么了 瓦妮莎?
What troubles you, Vanessa?
你看见朱利亚诺・美第奇了吗?
Have you seen Giuliano de Medici?
我要见他 我有话和他说
I must speak to him. He needs to hear this.
快点 别让大主教看见
Quickly, before the Cardinal sees.
确保这些圣饼送到美蒂奇家族那边
Ensure that these wafers go to the Medicis,
别出差错
and only the Medicis.
然后我们就能真正庆祝弥撒了
And then we can truly celebrate this mass.
复活节快乐 洛伦佐
Happy Easter, Lorenzo.
你也是 弗朗切斯科
And to you, Francesco.
朱利亚诺在哪?
Where is Giuliano?
我相信德拉戈纳迪会带他来的
I'm sure Dragonetti will bring him straight here.
我今天心里没底
I'm sure of nothing today.
上帝啊 莱昂 你昨夜到底去哪了?
God's trousers, Leo. Where the fuck have you been all night?
道别时纠缠了一下
Only haunted by a final farewell.
船装好货后 船长急着离岸
The barge is loaded and the captain's keen to depart.
那货威胁说再等的话 就把票价翻倍
Impatient canker blossom threatened to double the fee if he waited any longer.
好吧... 那咱省点钱
Well... then let's save some coin
赶快上船吧
and be on our way.
这是什么?
What's this?
我们用这占卜你到底是去哪里了
This is us asking the Fates where the fuck you've been.
战车 逆位的?
The Chariot. Reversed?
不受控制的激情 导致失败
Uncontrolled passion, leading to defeat.
我说该走了 走吧
Time to leave, I'd say. Come on.
太安静了
It's so quiet.
钟不响了
The bells have stopped.
弥撒开始了
Mass has begun.
该死
Fuck.
有件事我必须去做
There's something I must do.
- 没时间了  - 驳船不会等你的 你想清楚了
- There's no time.  - The barge won't wait. Make a decision.
叶之书还是女人 不可兼得啊
The Book Of Leaves or whoever tears you away. You can't have both.
我可以 我可以的 只要你们能想办法让船等我回来
I can. I can, if you just find a way to keep them here until I return.
我很快就回来 想想办法 琐罗
I'm not gonna be long. Just stall them, Zo.
求你了!
Please!
这就是那张牌的另一个意思
There's another meaning to that card.
被阻挡的旅途
A journey thwarted.
以圣父 圣子 圣灵之名
In nominee Patris, et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
- 阿门  - 阿门
- Amen.  - Amen.
你惧怕上帝吗 女士?
Do you fear God, Signora?
聪明的人... 对上帝应怀爱与惧之心
The wise... both fear and love God.
那你为什么犹豫不敢进入他的圣殿?
Why then do you hesitate to enter His house?
因为在门后等着我的并不是上帝
Because it isn't God who waits for me inside those doors.
聆听子民的祈祷 赐予他们想要的圣体
tui, cum oblationibus hostiarum:
如你在逾越节所作的
ut paschalibus initiata mysteriis,
您的赠与
ad aeternitatis  nobis medelam,
将带给我们救赎
te operante, proficiant.
借圣子耶稣之体
Per Dominum.
有人骑马接近
Riders approach.
两匹
Two.
厄运将降临在这座城市
Hell is descending upon this city.
快 找个安全地方躲起来
Get yourself to safety. Now.
你怎么了?
What has happened to you?
上帝不允许暴力
God will permit no violence.
你不能打断弥撒!
You cannot disrupt a sacred Mass!
- 放下武器!  - 很抱歉 我不能
- Sheathe your weapon!  - I'm sorry, but I cannot.
立即停止你的行为 这里是教堂
Cease your intrusion. This is a House of God.
上帝爱真相 让他说
And God loves truth. Let him speak.
帕吉家族密谋对付我们 我的家族!
The Pazzis conspire against us, my family!
他们与罗马结盟 他们背叛了佛罗伦萨!
They're in league with Rome and betray all Florence!
以人民和自由的名义! 消灭美第奇家族!
People and Liberty! Death to the Medicis!
快走 带女儿们去安全的地方
Go. Take our daughters to safety.
他们在大门口布置了人 找条路逃出去 快!
They'll have men at the doors. Find a way out. Go!
- 朱利亚诺!  - 洛伦佐啊!
- Giuliano!  - Lorenzo!
朝门那边跑
Towards the door.
你背叛了我们的事业 队长
You betray our cause, Captain.
你们的事业背叛了佛罗伦萨
Your cause betrays Florence.
快跑吧 女士! 这里面刀剑交加啊!
Flee, my lady! It is a chaos of swords in there!
杀光他们!
Kill them!
哥哥! 哥哥! 帮帮你的亲人!
Brother! Brother! Help your family!
罗马才是我的亲人
Rome is my family.
请原谅
Forgive me.
- 啊!  - 朱利亚诺!
- Aaargh!  - Giuliano!
死吧 美第奇渣滓!
Die, Medici scum!
他妻子和孩子 快 追!
The wife and children. Go, go!
朱利亚诺! 不!
Oh, Giuliano! Oh, no! No!
不!
No!
快跑!
Come on!
啊!
Aaargh!
克拉丽丝... 快!
Clarice... please!
快来
Come on.
我... 我要死了 瓦妮莎
I'm... I'm dying, Vanessa.
我将延续你的血脉
Your line will live on. In me.
我怀了你的孩子 你的儿子 朱利亚诺
I'm bearing your child, your son, Giuliano.
瓦妮莎 太晚了 瓦妮莎 快走吧
Vanessa, it's too late. Vanessa, leave him.
别管他了! 瓦妮莎!
Leave him! Vanessa!
- 不! 不!  - 快走吧
- No! No!  - Yes. Come on.
跟我来
Stay with me.
把剑扔掉 亲爱的表妹
Drop it, dear cousin.
不 不!
No, no!
你觉得我对付不了你们?
You imagine I can't take on the lot of you?
瑞阿里奥
Riario.
如果你真的忠诚于美第奇家 队长...
If your true loyalty is to the Medicis, Captain...
我建议你带他们走 这个留给我
I suggest you take them away and leave this one to me.
- 但多纳蒂夫人...  - 已经背叛你们投靠罗马了
- But Signora Donati...  - Has betrayed you for Rome.
让他们狗咬狗去吧 夫人
Leave them to each other, Signora.
孩子们
Children.
快走
Hurry.
不...
No...
我一直祈祷这一天的来临 今天 佛罗伦萨欢欣鼓舞
I've prayed for this day. Today, Florence rejoices.
你真以为会那样吗? 帕吉?
Are you certain of that, Pazzi?
啊!
Aaargh!
洛伦佐 临死之前
Before you die, Lorenzo,
让你知道 我将会杀尽佛罗伦萨所有美第奇家的人
know that I'll kill every last Medici in Florence.
我要将你家族的痕迹从世界上完全抹除!
I'll wipe all evidence of your family's existence from this world!
剑不用会生锈
Iron rusts from disuse.
让我们消灭美第奇家族 小作家
Let us finish off the Medicis, scribbler,
你还可以苟活
and we might let you live.
帕吉家族掌管佛罗伦萨? 绝不!
A Florence ruled by Pazzis? No!
我更愿意为此而战
No. I think I'd rather go down fighting.
遂你所愿
As you wish.
快点 快点!
Come on. Come on!
快点! 快点!
Come on! Come on!
- 那撑不了多久的  - 门能撑住
- That won't hold long.  - The doors will hold.
韦罗基奥设计的锁具
Verrocchio designed the locks.
朱利亚诺呢? 我弟弟死了吗?
Giuliano? Have I lost a brother?
给我砸! 砸开 砸开!
Come on! Come on, come on!
达芬奇!
Da Vinci!
我来的时候只看到你
Upon my arrival I saw only you.
- 我知道你不会不管我们的  - 别说了 省点劲吧
- I knew you wouldn't abandon us.  - Stop. Save your strength.
达芬奇!
Da Vinci!
很快就有结果啦 卢克蕾齐娅!
It'll be over soon, Lucrezia!
很抱歉 莱昂纳多 你救了我 我知道这对你来说...
I'm sorry, Leonardo. You've saved my life, and I know what it's cost y...
嘘 把你的赞美之词留给值得的人吧
Ssh. Save your praise for someone who deserves it.
你希望他们中的哪一个为你陪葬?
I wonder which of the two men you fuck will be buried alongside you?
你放弃梦想 选择了保卫佛罗伦萨
You chose Florence over your own dreams.
请接受我的敬意
You will accept my love.
我也只能向你致敬了
It is the least I can offer you.
这戒指 我认识这戒指
This ring. I know this ring.
这是卢克蕾齐娅的
It's Lucrezia's.
你跟她上床了... 或者更甚?
Are you fucking her... or is it more?
要么你现在帮他们干掉我 否则我发誓...
You better finish the job they have begun or I swear...
如果我们能生还 我要把你俩都杀掉
if we survive this, I'll kill you both.
领受上帝的复仇之怒吧!
God's vengeance is upon you!
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Spencer
翻译：落寞卷菜 潇妹纸 凌凡1991 Harry妹子 SceneryJuly Mabb
校对：sharefans_竺 影子